<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Publication on Titan de Tian</title>
    <link>https://ThisIsTian.github.io/publication/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Publication on Titan de Tian</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <managingEditor>xtiant1@gmail.com (Tiantian Xie)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>xtiant1@gmail.com (Tiantian Xie)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 22:14:44 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://ThisIsTian.github.io/publication/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Real-time Subsurface Control Variates: Temporally Stable Adaptive Sampling</title>
      <link>https://ThisIsTian.github.io/publication/real-time-subsurface-control-variates/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 22:14:44 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>xtiant1@gmail.com (Tiantian Xie)</author>
      <guid>https://ThisIsTian.github.io/publication/real-time-subsurface-control-variates/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;publication-preview-teaser&#34;&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;publication-page&#34;&gt;
&lt;image src=&#34;../../Image/publication/i3d2021/RegularLighting_Scene_171.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/image&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;project-page&#34;&gt;
&lt;image src=&#34;../../Image/publication/i3d2021/Teaser.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/image&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;teaser-caption&#34;&gt;
Figure 1: Dynamic subsurface scene just after light has been turned off. Our method has consistently lower
          sample count (d) than SPVG [Xie et al. 2020] (c) at this frame. It leads to lower sampling pass time in dynamic
          lighting from 12.9 ms to 5.2 ms at 3360 × 1440 (×2.5), while maintaining good quality (47.5 dB) vs SPVG (48.6
          dB). Separable (b) runs fastest for the whole subsurface pass at 4.0 ms, however, with visible banding artifacts.
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: justify; word-wrap: break-word; font-size:14px&#34;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Abstract&lt;/em&gt;: Real-time adaptive sampling is a new technique recently proposed for efficient importance sampling in real-time
            Monte Carlo sampling in subsurface scattering. It adaptively places samples based on variance tracking
            to help escape the uncanny valley of subsurface rendering. However, the occasional performance drop due to
            temporal lighting dynamics (e.g., guns or lights turning on and off) could hinder adoption in games or other
            applications where smooth high frame rate is preferred. In this paper we propose a novel usage of Control
            Variates (CV) in the sample domain instead of shading domain to maintain a consistent low pass time. Our
            algorithm seamlessly reduces to diffuse with zero scattering samples for sub-pixel scattering. We propose a
            novel joint-optimization algorithm for sample count and CV coefficient estimation. The main enabler is our
            novel time-variant covariance updating method that helps remove the effect of recent temporal dynamics
            from variance tracking. Since bandwidth is critical in real-time rendering, a solution without adding any extra
            textures is also provided.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--- #### Download #### ---&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;font size = &#34;2&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;downloadable&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;../../publication/I3D_2021_preprint.pdf&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div&gt;
    &lt;image style=&#34;float: left; width: 12pt; vertical-align:middle&#34; src=&#34;../../icons8-pdf-40.png&#34;/&gt;
    &lt;span&gt;Preprint (51.3 MB PDF)&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;downloadable&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;../../publication/I3D_2021_preprint_low_res.pdf&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div&gt;
    &lt;image style=&#34;float: left; width: 12pt; vertical-align:middle&#34; src=&#34;../../icons8-pdf-40.png&#34;/&gt;
    &lt;span&gt;Preprint-small (7.1 MB PDF)&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class = &#34;downloadable&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;../../publication/I3D_2021_supplementary_low_res.pdf&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div&gt;
    &lt;image style=&#34;float: left; width: 12pt; vertical-align:middle&#34; src=&#34;../../icons8-pdf-40.png&#34;/&gt;
    &lt;span&gt;Supplementary (642 KB PDF)&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Real-time subsurface scattering with single pass variance-guided adaptive importance sampling</title>
      <link>https://ThisIsTian.github.io/publication/real-time-subsurface-with-adaptive-sampling/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2020 08:45:22 -0800</pubDate>
      <author>xtiant1@gmail.com (Tiantian Xie)</author>
      <guid>https://ThisIsTian.github.io/publication/real-time-subsurface-with-adaptive-sampling/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;publication-preview-teaser&#34;&gt;
&lt;image src=&#34;../../Image/publication/i3d2020/subsurfaceteaser.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/image&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;teaser-caption&#34;&gt;
Figure 1: Subsurface rendering comparison from close to far at 1920x1080 on NVIDIA Quadro P4000 (implemented in UE4). (a) our adaptive sampling algorithm ($σ\\_0^2$ = 0.001, κ = 0.2, $b\\_{min}$ = 8 spp, $b\\_{max}$ = 64 spp), (b) Golubev [2018]’s sampling model in our framework with 64spp, (c) a Baseline fixed 64-sample implementation without our proposed acceleration techniques, (d) Separable screen-space diffusion. (e) Visualization of our adaptive sample count for each view. Our quality is higher than Baseline in all three scenarios (close skin patch, ear, and front). Moreover, our algorithm runs faster on the close skin patch with an acceleration of up to 91.07× (2.78 ms vs 253.18 ms). In addition, our algorithm enables better quality with run time comparable or even better than Separable. Error measurements are PSNR for the subsurface, as compared to a reference image at 2k samples per pixel. Digital Mike ©Epic Games, Inc.
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: justify; word-wrap: break-word; font-size:14px&#34;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Abstract&lt;/em&gt;: In real-time applications, it is difficult to simulate realistic subsurface scattering with differing degrees
translucency. Burley’s reflectance approximation by empirically fitting the diffusion profile as a whole makes
it possible to achieve realistic looking subsurface scattering for different translucent materials in screen
space. However, achieving a physically correct result requires real-time Monte Carlo sampling of the analytic
importance function per pixel per frame, which seems prohibitive to achieve. In this paper, we propose an
approximation of the importance function that can be evaluated in real-time. Since subsurface scattering
is more pronounced in certain regions (e.g., with light gradient change), we propose an adaptive sampling
method based on temporal variance to lower the required number of samples. We propose a one phase
adaptive sampling pass that is unbiased, and able to adapt to scene changes due to motion and lighting.
To further improve the quality, we explore temporal reuse with a guiding pass prior to the final temporal
anti-aliasing (TAA) phase that further improves the quality. Our local guiding pass does not constrain the
TAA implementation, and only requires one additional texture to be passed between frames. Our proposed
variance-guided algorithm has the potential to make stochastic sampling algorithm effective for real-time
rendering.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--- #### Download #### ---&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;font size = &#34;2&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class = &#34;downloadable&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;../../publication/spvg_xie_2020_I3D.pdf&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div&gt;
    &lt;image style=&#34;float: left; width: 12pt; vertical-align:middle&#34; src=&#34;../../icons8-pdf-40.png&#34;/&gt;
    &lt;span&gt;Preprint (75 MB PDF)&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class = &#34;downloadable&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;../../publication/spvg_xie_2020_I3D_small.pdf&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div&gt;
    &lt;image style=&#34;float: left; width: 12pt; vertical-align:middle&#34; src=&#34;../../icons8-pdf-40.png&#34;/&gt;
    &lt;span&gt;Preprint-small (7.3 MB PDF)&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class = &#34;downloadable&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dl.acm.org/doi/10.1145/3384536&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div&gt;
    &lt;image style=&#34;float: left; width: 12pt;vertical-align:middle&#34; src=&#34;../../icons8-home-40.png&#34;/&gt;
    &lt;span&gt;Publisher&#39;s homepage&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>